# Tameika Reed

Saint Petersburg, FL

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Tameika-Reed/4a58a47f96d11c26

# **Professional Summary**

Senior Architect of 20 years currently, TS/SCI with CI Poly. Currently working on designing Kubernetes clusters for various vendors in the Airforce. This includes automation, creating continuous integration, deployment, testing, and compliance pipelines. Developed a curriculum for cloud migration, cloud deployment, security standards and hardening. Leading teams on SCIF standards for accreditation, creating automation, cloud migration, and designing pipelines with Gitlab-CI and Jenkins.

# Work Experience

# **Senior Infrastructure Engineer**

Octoml-Seattle, WA

August 2020 to Present

- \* Install applications using Git-Ops with Multi-cloud strategy (AWS, GCP, and Azure)
- \* GitLab-CI and GitHub Actions for CI/CD
- \* Deploying cloud strategies using Terraform, Ansible, Packer, and Git.
- \* Automating TVM using Jenkins with multi-cloud executors
- \* Security automation and scanning of infrastructure
- \* Setup datacenter with various GPUS

#### **Director of Strategy and Innovation/Consultant**

Expansia-Nashua, NH

October 2018 to June 2021

- \* Install and set up Terraform Enterprise using Vault and Consul backends
- High Availability with DR (disaster recovery)
- Deployment = 50 nodes
- \* Implement Static and Dynamic secrets with Vault cluster
- \* Install and implement Consul instances
- \* Security automation and scanning of infrastructure
- \* Set up Git Ops pipeline for immutable infrastructure
- Using Gitlab and Gitlab-CI
- Deploying STIG machine images and containers
- Deploying Kubernetes and application to cluster
- Deploying infrastructure using Terraform
- Analyze service mesh and training the team on the differences
- ∘ Istio
- Envoy
- Consul Connect
- ∘ VMware NSX-T
- \* Train teams on the following:
- Immutable infrastructure

- Service Mesh
- Terraform
- Git Ops
- Vault
- Terraform Enterprise
- Continuous security, testing, integration, and deployment pipeline
- \* Use the principles of Observability with cluster and applications setup
- Retrieving Private Terraform Enterprise metrics
- PostgreSQL Databases
- Retrieving application metrics
- Open Tracing Platform recommendations:
- \* Zipkin
- \* Jaeger
- \* Setup of Hybrid Cloud using the following tools:
- VMware current
- AWS planned migration
- Kubernetes vanilla
- OpenShift planned migration and hybrid cloud
- Rancher on prem migration
- \* Train How to use the Satellite Server with Ansible Tower
- Benefits of using Puppet and Ansible
- How to set up Satellite Server and Capsule
- Capsules how to use and its benefits
- Ansible functionality for configuration management using cloud-native applications
- \* Set up continuous delivery of Windows applications
- Using GitLab Runner to run CI/CD pipelines
- Continuous security scanning of applications (vulnerability and security)
- Continuous deployment of applications
- Continuous testing, security scanning, and monitoring of clusters, applications, and containers
- Weighing the options of using SCCM and its effectiveness

#### **Technical Area Lead**

General Dynamics-Chantilly, VA April 2018 to October 2018

- \* Transitioned 10-12 person team to a DevOps methodology
- \* Implemented automation using GitLab, Jenkins, Jira, TDD and CI/CD technologies
- \* Automated the onboarding process of new customers for mission critical purposes
- Involving gathering data requirements
- Application and package requirements
- Bandwidth and Security requirements
- Deployment availability
- Service level agreements
- Start and shutdown testing to be done anytime
- Power requirements
- \* Onboarded new customers ranging from 50-200 desktops/workstations/servers using the Ansible, Puppet, and the Satellite Server 6.x
- \* Automating installs of server services using Ansible, Hammer (Satellite Server), Terraform (AWS)

- \* Deployed workstations and other servers using Puppet.
- \* Used Puppet to keep the workstations/desktops/servers STIG Compliant
- \* Facilitated brown bag sessions of different infrastructure automation technologies
- \* Designed and implemented team cross training
- \* Facilitated a peer review that allows for rotation of information
- \* Created design documentation for research/development, new services, and deployment
- \* Automated STIG/OSCAP/Nessus scans using the API calls through staging with Jenkins
- \* Integrated Red Hat Identity Manager (IDM) and Active Directory (AD) to maintain a consistent user profile across client information systems
- \* Automated certified testing plan for all services and deployments
- \* Shadowed team members to understand BP and redesign the flow to DevOps style
- \* Designed and implemented Elasticsearch with X-pack and packet beat to show lags in overall network performance
- \* Brought in new people to train up on automation that were normally windows admins
- \* Security redesign of Selina's using MLS
- \* Designed and implemented our Zabbix server for monitoring and alerting
- \* Redesign the Backups implementation Backups
- \* Used Packer to automate the image process of building AMIS
- \* Automated build process for creating ISOs
- \* Designed initial migration phase to OpenShift for infrastructure deployment
- Gather security requirements
- How to deploy and scale containers
- Immutable infrastructure
- Jira and Confluence workflows

#### **Senior Cloud Architect**

Spathe Systems-Tampa, FL January 2018 to March 2018

- $^{*}$  Designed and built a private cloud for SOCOM. The project was a test plan to migrate 10,000 Microsoft applications initially, then 30,000 applications to microservices using OpenSource
- \* Implemented workflow using GitLab, Spinnaker, qcow2 instances from isos, Kubernetes, Docker, security hardening using STIGs, and separation of data and duty using SELinux MLS
- \* Analyzed teams existing applications to transition into developer's workflow

#### **Principal System Engineer**

CACI/BITS/LTC-Sarasota, FL

March 2011 to December 2017

- \* Researched and developed environments for future programs using Qubes OS and OpenShift
- \* Migrated infrastructure over to Centrify, Kerberos, IPA, LDAP, and IDM for 120 Linux workstation/server logins
- \* Reconfigured the infrastructure from VMware to Openstack to 40 users in sandbox (sensitive data- no cloud (unclassified)
- \* Migrated a VMware project to AWS, involved setting up VPC, Security, Scaling, Load Balancing, and Architecting (classified)
- \* Moved desktops to a VDI solution (project dependent)
- \* Set up testing/tested cases for logging servers in Splunk, Syslog, and ELK Stack
- \* Used Docker containers for services such Foreman, Nginx, Katello, LDAP and various services (provisioning)
- \* Managed 2,000 machines for deployments, security, patching, live migrations, and live missions

- \* Ensured accreditation to 503(c)(1) accreditation and NIST framework
- \* Created Puppet playbooks and modules to ensure system hardening of infrastructure, desktops, and all hardware
- \* Used Nessus, SELinux, OpenSCAP, Nessus scans and STIGs for security hardening of VM, containers, and hosts
- \* Automated installs using Puppet, Chef, Ansible, Terraform (IAAS), and scripting using bash, python, and go(beginner)
- \* Positioned infrastructure strategies for growth as well as maintaining high availability and backups
- \* Purchased storage based on growing infrastructure needs
- \* Day-to-day responsibility for infrastructure for 6 projects and networks including upgrades, migrations, troubleshooting, and new technology research
- \* Built Satellite Server 5, 6, used for security and maintenance of the entire infrastructure, containers, and instances
- \* Developed session and trained team Being a Solutions Architect with supporting documentation
- \* Storage Administration with NetApp, EMC, Dell, and HP services
- \* Designed NFS Storage for 300 users
- \* Set up, installed, configured and deployed VMware, VMware Workstation, and VCloud
- \* Trained members on various topics
- Cloud architecture
- Security in the cloud
- Containers
- Auto scaling
- \* Kickstarted, automated and provisioned Centos/RHEL 4, 5, 6, 7 servers and workstations
- \* Trained team on continuous deployment (Jenkins), Git, architecting, auto scaling and backups
- \* Deployed OpenStack and Kubernetes for various projects
- \* Used GCP and Amazon for hybrid cloud solution, project dependent
- \* Performance tuning and standardization of Linux installs and upgrades
- \* System monitoring with Prometheus and Zabbix

## **Senior Linux Systems Administrator**

SAIC-Alexandria, VA

October 2008 to 2011

- \* Administrated facilities that help develop cutting edge technologies to aid intelligence operations in support of active and ongoing US troop deployments.
- \* Supported server suites running Linux that host multiple applications including ESRI products
- \* Created and rebuilt RPMS for deployment
- \* Configured multiple server tools such as Apache, MySQL, OpenLDAP and PXE
- \* Developed and maintained CM/process book tracking hardware/software configuration and processes for upgrades/recovery
- \* Day-to-day duties required advanced knowledge of networking protocols, DNS, SNMP, OpenMosix, MRTG, SSH, VPNs, Juniper firewalls and virtualization using VM Ware and XEN
- \* Worked with multiple Linux platforms such as Red Hat, CentOS, Fedora and Ubuntu
- \* Managed personnel on various Linux administration projects and assignments in conjunction with other ongoing projects sharing lab space. Troubleshot hardware/software problems
- \* Set up SAN storage using EMC and NetApp sans. Created a build environment for developing rpms for different applications
- \* Created, installed, and configured Confluence, Crowd, Jira, and Fisheye
- \* Networking responsibilities included setting up Cisco, 3Com, HP, Dells switches and blades for various projects. Installed, managed, and maintained backup solutions using Veritas, rsnapshot, and Data Domain

## **Senior Systems Engineer**

L3-Communications-Alexandria, VA April 2008 to October 2008

- \* Engineered the support and maintenance of large-scale production networks and systems, including the design and development of tools and scripts to assist with such maintenance.
- \* Designed, integrated, and maintained network services such as DNS, DHCP, SMB, SNMP, Radius, Kerberos, electronic mail, LDAP directories, IPSEC virtual private networks and firewalls applications
- \* Automated daily processes using Perl, PHP, and Python. Designs and develops high-performance groups of servers for resource-intensive network applications
- \* Designed, archived and created backup systems
- \* Worked closely with technical staff to ensure that backup and archived designs and procedures were implemented properly
- \* Planned and implemented system security policies, to include firewalls, host/client access, file permissions, and user accounts
- \* Developed best practices, operational procedures and design documentation
- \* Planned and coordinated system utilization, performed growth analysis and capacity planning
- \* Reviewed current systems and made technical/process recommendations for improving efficiency
- \* Provided on-call technical support to clients regarding operational/applications issues
- \* Installed and debugged new/upgraded software on server and client platforms
- $^{\ast}$  Diagnosed networks, systems, and applications to identify and correct malfunctions and other operational problems

## **Replications Systems Administrator**

Nortel Government Solutions-San Antonio, TX July 2007 to April 2008

- \* Replicated US Courts servers by performing backups and restoration of databases using Informix
- \* Performed daily maintenance, troubleshooting, and error correction of the Linux server environment with Hewitt Packard hardware and SAN storage
- \* Migrated Red Hat Enterprise 3 to Red Hat Enterprise 5 with virtualization by creating Xen guests, backing up those guests to tapes, and SAN storage
- \* Created Perl, Python and bash scripts for daily tasks, Xen configuration files, and logical volume manager (lvm)
- \* Researched and configured GFS clusters for failover situations

Rack Space Managed Hosting - San Antonio, TX March 2007 - July 2007

Managed Backup Administer I

- \* Conducted backups and installs, restored failures on Linux and Windows Systems in a CommVault and Legoto environment
- \* Performed advanced command line administration and Windows (Server 2003 and XP) Administration
- \* Managed incoming client failures from file system recovery to MySQL Database re-construction

#### **Linux System Administrator**

University of Washington-Seattle, WA March 2006 to May 2007

- \* Managed 20 Linux Cluster nodes utilized by 50+ users
- \* Created Apache, Subversion, Lamp, and MySQL/PostgreSQL servers for data sharing amongst students and faculty
- \* Installed software packages, Linux applications, and created new user accounts and groups quarterly
- \* Monitored and enhanced operating environments using OpenMosix and environmental software to ensure optimal performance
- \* Applied software patches and wrote command procedures and programs to eliminate operating errors

- \* Conducted needs assessments, requirements analysis and evaluated products for applications, computing, and/or telecommunication technologies that were applicable to the needs of the Computational Linguistics Graduate Department
- \* Worked on developing a Java Cluster, using Terracotta, to balance out user processes amongst several machines as opposed to one

## **Linux System Administrator**

Advanced Acoustics Concepts-Bremerton, WA June 2001 to October 2005

- \* Part of a team that developed and maintained advanced defense systems for the Department of Defense
- \* Designed and implemented classified secure LAN to meet and exceed NISPOM chapter 8 requirements
- \* Developed automation scripts and procedures for software development and code reviews
- \* Administered network for local corporate office and coordinated with peers nationally to work on company wide tasks
- \* Trained and tasked with interns, from coding to maintaining integrated Windows/Linux environment
- \* Administered Windows 98, 2000, XP Home, XP Pro, and Solaris 10, RedHat, and Fedora 4 servers in a client/server environment for 3 years.
- \* Assisted with build out of SCIF for accreditation using linux as a primary domain controller, Samba, and pGina
- \* In depth knowledge in Linux internals, including the boot process using GRUB and LILO, how to use and initialize the X window managers, TCP networking and Linux network configuration (with an emphasis on wireless networking), package management (.rpm, .deb, .tgz), the Linux kernel compilation process, how kernel modules work, and how to debug programs using GDB

#### Education

#### **Masters**

Capella University

September 2010 to December 2012

# **Bachelors in Computer Engineering Technology**

DeVry University - Federal Way, WA March 2004 to March 2007

#### B.S.

University of Washington - Tacoma, WA March 2003 to June 2003

## Associate in Science (AS) in Computer Engineering

Olympic College - Bremerton, WA March 2002 to September 2002

#### Skills

- OpenStack
- Certified
- Linux Skills
- Expert
- Backup Skills

- Expert
- Security+
- Certified
- Security Hardening
- Expert
- Infrastructure/Automation Buildout
- Expert
- Security Skills
- Expert
- GCP/Azure/AWS/Cloud -Advanced
- Terraform/Ansible/Puppet
- Advanced
- Kubernetes
- Advanced
- OpenShift
- Intermediate
- Docker
- Expert
- Vault/Consul/Service Mesh
- Advanced
- Terraform Enterprise
- Expert
- APIs
- Git
- Jenkins
- Scripting
- Shell Scripting
- MySQL
- Java
- DNS
- Creating Infrastructure for AI/ML/Deep Learning
- TCP/IP
- XML
- VMWare
- Apache
- CI/CD
- DevOps
- Operating Systems
- SQL
- Load Balancing

- Active Directory
- Computer Networking
- Tomcat
- Jira
- Authentication
- Continuous integration
- AWS
- PowerShell